

Bjørnar Moe Remmen

Software developer





A developer with experiences within machine learning and backend development. As a developer I really like the challenge machine learning gives and the ability to be creative. The last year I also completed a course in Parallel Programming covering CUDA, OpenMPI and basic pthread & openmp use.

Experience

Microchip

Application Engineer • Aug, 2020 - Present

Writing software both for microcontrollers in C and general backend development.

Capgemini

Data Scientist • Jan, 2019 — Aug, 2020

Worked with a team that specializing in Computer Vision. One of my projects at a startup that used underwater cameras in fish farms was to try to create a program to monitor the health of the fish using Computer Vision.

Making Waves

Data Scientist • Jul, 2017 — Dec, 2018

Worked as a general developer and Data Scientist. Two of the projects including Machine Learning were a Norwegian Chatbot project in python and Proof of Concept testing Computer Vision in Elastic Search.

Kodeklubben Trondheim

Instructor - Internship • Jun, 2016 — Jul, 2016

Kodeklubben is a Norwegian initative to teach children coding. This internship was about teaching HTMl, CSS, JavaScript to people from junior high school and high school.

Education

Norwegian University of Science and Technology - NTNU

Informatics, M.Sc., Artificial Intelligence • 2015 — 2017

Sør-Trøndelag University COllege - HiST

Computer Science, B.Sc. • 2012 — 2015

Projects

SEALAB OCEAN GROUP

Developer • March 2019 — August 2019

Sealab is a provider of under water cameras that is used in fish farming for monitoring fish. To be able to monitor the fishes health, I was a consultant helping to get further in the computer vision goal of monitoring fish and wounds.

Matprat.no — Chatbot in Norwegian

Developer • March 2018 — June 2018

Matprat is a food recipe website, and the end result provided for them was a chatbot that could answer food safety questions and give suggetions on what to make based on what ingredients the person has. The reason do do this was to give a better user experience for the user when looking for recipes and to avoid food waste.

Skills

Parallel Progamming

Took a course in 2020 at NTNU in parallel rogramming that covered CUDA, OpenMPI, OpenMP and Pthreads. Implemented Convolution in OpenMPI and CUDA getting Ideas from the paper Ghost Cell Pattern

Recognition

Global Data Science Challenge 2020 - 1st place

Capgemini • 2020

The Capgemini Data Science Challenge was a colaboration between Amazon and Capgemini. The challenge was to identify sperm whales by their fluke to help to monitor the whales.

Associations

School Bar

Volunteer • 2001 — 2010

The School bar is used by both engineers and other diciplines to socialize. Some responsibilities I had were to work behind the bar and checking IDs at the entrance.

Additional Links

• Capgemini Global Datascience Challenge - Using AI to protect sperm whales